A Guide to the James Frederick Dudley Collection, 1927-1929
Special Collections, Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University
Special Collections, Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University
James Frederick Dudley Collection, 1927-1929
Special Collections, Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University, Blacksburg, Va.
Ms1949-002
1 box; 0.2 cu. ft.
The collection contains programs, clippings, and fliers from organizations in which Dudley participated while a student at VPI, including the Dramatic Club, the Bugle, the Tech Minstrels, the Southwestern Virginia Chemical Club, and the YMCA.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
The James Frederick Dudley Collection was donated to Special Collections prior to 1949.
Biographical Information
James Frederick Dudley graduated from VPI in 1929 with a degree in Chemical Engineering. He was involved with the Dramatic and Chemical Clubs from his sophomore through senior years. During his senior year, he also served in the YMCA Cabinet and as the Photographic Manager of the Bugle.
See page 98 of the 1929 Bugle (page 106 of the pdf) for a senior photograph of Dudley.
Scope and Content
The collection contains programs, clippings, and fliers from organizations in which Dudley participated while a student at VPI, including the Dramatic Club, the Bugle, the Tech Minstrels, the Southwestern Virginia Chemical Club, and the YMCA.
A majority of this collection consists of ticket stubs, reviews, and news articles on Dramatic Club productions performed between 1927 and 1929, including "Miss Patricia," "Mrs. Bumpstead Leigh," "Charm School," and "Tech Scandals." Also included are materials relating to Dramatic Club-sponsored events, and the club constitution and proceedings.
YMCA materials include blank letterhead, news-clippings, and internal organization notes. Tech Minstrel materials relate to Bugle-sponsored concert events. The collection also includes Bugle letterhead. Chemistry Club ephemera relates to the completion of Davidson Hall and also contains a note denying Dudley's request to wear civilian clothes to a club banquet.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged by subject matter.
Contents List
- Bugle and Tech Minstrels, 1927-1929. (Box-folder 1:1)
- Davidson Hall/Southwestern Virginia Chemical Club, 1927-1928. (Box-folder 1:2)
- Dramatic Club, Constitution and Proceedings, 1928. (Box-folder 1:3)
- Dramatic Club, "Miss Patricia," 1927. (Box-folder 1:4)
- Dramatic Club, "Mrs. Bumpstead Leigh," 1928. (Box-folder 1:5)
- Dramatic Club, "The Wishing Well," 1928. (Box-folder 1:6)
- Dramatic Club, "Charm School," 1929. (Box-folder 1:7)
- Dramatic Club, "Tech Scandals," 1929. (Box-folder 1:8)
- YMCA, 1928-1929. (Box-folder 1:9)
- Miscellany, including: band and football ephemera, dues receipts, and waitership lists, 1927-1929. (Box-folder 1:10)